Finding aid to Record Group 9. Photographs, of the YWCA of the U.S.A. records SSC.MS.00324.RG9
Sophia Smith Collection
- Prints and negatives, 1
  - International Work, D
    - Ethiopia: Vocational training, circa 1960-1971 (Box 1007, Folder 5)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association vocational training programs in Ethiopia. These schools offer classes in domestic arts, sewing, cooking, literacy and English. Photographs highlight class accomplishments and participants and include images of active classes and graduation ceremonies.
      Ethiopia; Young Women's Christian Associations -- Ethiopia; Women -- Ethiopia; Cooking -- Study and teaching -- Ethiopia; Leadership in women; Literacy -- Ethiopia; Children -- Ethiopia; Child care services -- Ethiopia; Vocational guidance -- Ethiopia; Adult education of women -- Ethiopia
    - Fiji, circa 1960-1972 (Box 1007, Folder 6)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association programs and activities in Fiji. Photographs include images of vocation and skills training classes, special events, kindergarten classes and YWCA buildings.
      Fiji; Young Women's Christian associations -- Fiji; Women -- Fiji; Leadership in women; Literacy -- Fiji; Children -- Fiji; Child care services -- Fiji; Vocational guidance -- Fiji; Adult education of women -- Fiji; Recreation -- Fiji
    - Finland, circa 1950-1959 (Box 1007, Folder 7)
      Photograph of a young women's Christian association youth program director teaching a craft project in a YWCA of the USA association in the United States. The Finish leader is part of a YWCA of the USA training program for international YWCA leaders that encourages international understanding and the sharing of ideas and practices.
      Finland; Young Women's Christian associations -- Finland; Women -- Finland; Leadership in women
    - France, circa 1918-1970 (Box 1007, Folder 8)
      [see also Subseries E. Program, War Work: WWI]
      Photographs of young women's Christian associations activities and programs in France. These programs provide social, educational and recreational opportunities for its women and girls. Following World War II the work of YWCA's focuses on recovery and as part of this effort, YWCA of the USA associations donate a service center for underprivileged youth in Paris. Photograph captions indicate that this center is the only available place for the youth of Paris to go. It provides childcare for children of working families, recreation opportunities, craft activities and a place for the children to escape the streets of Paris. Additional photographs include images of early YWCA members performing tableaus, YWCA buildings, classes and women at a convention panel.
      France; Young Women's Christian associations -- France; Women -- France; Leadership in women; Children -- France; Reconstruction (1939-1951); Youth -- France
    - Germany: General, circa 1945-1959 (Box 1007, Folder 9)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association buildings and programs in Germany. Following World War II young women's Christian associations in Germany become a place for people of all ages to gather. The World YWCA sends workers to assist in establishing programs and donate materials that local women then reuse and repurpose into clothing. Several photographs show women piecing American neckties into skirts. Additional photographs shor the Neighborhood House in Berlin, a center known as being a friendly and welcoming place. Photographs show women and children enjoying its classes and facilities.
      Germany; Young Women's Christian associations -- Germany; Leadership in women; Children -- Germany; Reconstruction (1939-1951); Youth -- Germany; Sewing -- Germany; Refugees -- Germany; World Young Women's Christian Association
    - Germany: Children rebuilding, circa 1945-1960 (Box 1007, Folder 10)
      Photographs of children and youth participating in cleanup activities following World War II. Young people contribute to clean up projects by collecting materials, moving rubble and gardening. Many photographs feature the Neighborhood House in Berlin.
      Germany; Young Women's Christian associations -- Germany; Leadership in women; Children -- Germany; Reconstruction (1939-1951); Youth -- Germany
    - Germany: Negatives (Box 1007, Folder 11-12)
    - Germany: Neighborhood House, 1961-1962 (Box 1008, Folder 1)
      The Neighborhood House in Berlin, Germany hosts programs and activities for its community members young and old. This scrapbook, prepared for the YWCA of the USA highlights, house activities and includes photographs of a playground made possible by the contributions of the YWCA of New York. Additional Neighborhood House photographs feature classes and activities and each photograph is captioned on the back.
      scrapbooks; Germany; Berlin, Berlin, Germany; Young Women's Christian associations -- Germany; Women -- Germany; Children -- Germany; Youth -- Germany; Adult education -- Germany
    - Germany: Teens and children, circa 1945-1959 (Box 1008, Folder 2)
      Photographs of German young women's Christian association programs for teenagers and children. Programs for children include craft classes, summer camps and community service. For teens, coed groups engage in club planning and social activities. Many photographs feature the activities of the Neighborhood House in Berlin.
      Germany; Young Women's Christian associations -- Germany; Women -- Germany; Children -- Germany; Youth -- Germany; Teenage boys -- Germany; Teenage girls -- Germany; Outdoor recreation -- Germany
    - Ghana, 1961-1983 (Box 1008, Folder 3)
      Photographs of young women's Christian associations in Ghana. YWCA programs provide needed services for the children and women of the community including day care, recreation programs, social activities and classes. Photographs feature the dedication ceremonies for a new day care center, a car wash fundraiser at a local Mobil station and association meetings.
      Young Women's Christian associations -- Ghana; Women -- Ghana; Children -- Ghana; Youth -- Ghana; Outdoor recreation -- Ghana; Child care services -- Ghana; Ghana
    - Greece, circa 1920-1973 (Box 1008, Folder 4)
      [See also: Turkey, Smyrna Scrapbook]
      Photographs of young women's Christian association programs and services in Greece. Early work in Greece focuses on war relief and aid to refugees. The photographs show refugee camps, Greek, Armenian and Turkish refugees, and examples of relief efforts. Several photograph show crowds in front of a palace in Athens waiting for admission. Later YWCA activity takes on a form more familiar to established clubs around the world. The YWCA offers classes, child care and recreation.
      Greece; Young Women's Christian associations -- Greece; Women -- Greece; Children -- Greece; Youth -- Greece; Child care services -- Greece; Refugees -- Greece; Refugee camps -- Greece; Refugees -- Turkey; Refugee camps -- Turkey; Social work education -- Greece
    - Guyana, 1973 (Box 1008, Folder 5)
      Photographs of classes and the opening ceremony of a young women's Christian association school for girls who were "early school leavers."
      Guyana; Young Women's Christian associations -- Guyana; Women -- Guyana; Youth -- Guyana; Education -- Guyana
    - Hong Kong, circa 1938-1971 (Box 1008, Folder 6)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association activities in Hong Kong. Photograph show child care programs, folk dances, arts programs, buildings, adult education classes and the daily life of the associations.
      Young Women's Christian associations -- Hong Kong; Women -- Hong Kong; Youth -- Hong Kong; Refugees -- Hong Kong; Children -- Hong Kong; Hong Kong, China
    - Hungary, circa 1920-1929 (Box 1008, Folder 7)
      Postcard with image of three girls from Kalocsa, Hungary.
      Postcards; Women -- Hungary; Kalocsa -- Bács-Kiskun -- Hungary
    - India: Buildings, 1865-1963 (Box 1008, Folder 8)
      Interior and exterior photographs of young women's Christian association buildings in India.
      Young Women's Christian associations -- India; Women -- India; Youth -- India; Children -- India; Education -- India; India
    - India: Children, circa 1920-1970 (Box 1008, Folder 9)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association programs for youth in India. Programs include, nursery and preschool programs that provide care and education to young people while their mothers work and meal programs that provide necessary nutrition to those in need. Photographs include images of children in nursery care programs, village chilldren, supplemental nutrition programs and children enjoying play.
      Young Women's Christian associations -- India; Women -- India; Youth -- India; Children -- India; Education -- India; Child care services -- India; India
    - India: Classes, 1910-1970, bulk 1960-1970 (Box 1009, Folder 1)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association classes in India. The YWCA offers classes in literacy, crafts and vocational skills. These classes help empower women and train them in skills that may lead to better work and opportunities. Images feature students and instructors engaged in classroom activities.
      India; Young Women's Christian associations -- India; Women -- India; Youth -- India; Children -- India; Education -- India; Basic Education -- India; Literacy -- India; Vocational guidance -- India
    - India: Customs and religious practices, circa 1960-1970 (Box 1009, Folder 2)
      Photographs depicting religious and social customs in India.
      Young Women's Christian associations -- India; Women -- India; Youth -- India; Women -- Religious life -- India; India; India -- Religious life and customs
    - India: Education and recreation, circa 1902-1973 (Box 1009, Folder 3)
      Recreation, education and physical education are an important part of young women's Christian associations around the world. These images from India show women and girls participating in hikes, gym class, sports and social dances. Several photographs show a meeting between an American YWCA staff member and university students visiting India from. Additional photographs feature members of the Y-Teen program in India.
      India; Young Women's Christian associations -- India; Women -- India; Youth -- India; Physical education for women -- India; Recreation -- India; Outdoor recreation -- India; Teenage girls -- India
    - India: Girls Town, circa 1960-1969 (Box 1009, Folder 4)
      Girls Town is a home for homeless girls run by the YWCA of Madras, India. The home provides the girls with shelter, lessons and meals. Photographs show the daily activities of the girls in the home such as gardening, meals, prayers, chores and their daily walk to school. Additional photographs include images of potential new arrivals.
      India; Young Women's Christian associations -- India; Women -- India; Youth -- India; Homeless girls -- India; Children -- India; Basic needs -- India
    - India: Groups and conferences, 1911-1966 (Box 1009, Folder 5)
      Group photographs from young women's Christian associations in India. Photographs include images of conferences, meetings and programs.
      India; Young Women's Christian associations -- India; Women -- India; Youth -- India; Congresses and conventions -- India
    - India: Health, 1914-1970, bulk 1962-1970 (Box 1009, Folder 6)
      Photographs from health and health education programs of young women's Christian associations in India. Health education and treatment is a priority of club work in India, especially in rural areas. YWCA centers offer programs that include basic medical care, nutrition and health education. For rural areas, access to safe drinking water is also an important component to a health program. Photographs show women and families waiting for medical treatment, clean water projects, women at clinic appointments and children receiving milk as supplemental nutrition. Additional photographs include images of nurses training to give care, rural communities near YWCA centers and health education classes.
      India; Young Women's Christian associations -- India; Women -- India; Youth -- India; Health education of women -- India; Rural health services -- India; Food relief -- India
    - India: Miscellaneous, circa 1931-1979 (Box 1009, Folder 7)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association leaders, activities and buildings in India.
      Young Women's Christian associations -- India; Women -- India; Youth -- India; Education -- India
    - India: Negatives (Box 1009, Folder 8-10)
    - India: Nutrition project, 1963 (Box 1009, Folder 11)
      The nutrition project of the young women's Christian association in Bombay, India provides education to local women on basic nutrition and hygiene. Photographs show nutrition and cooking lessons as well as women and children engaged in meal preparations.
      Mumbai -- India; Young Women's Christian associations -- India; Women -- India; Youth -- India; Education -- India; Health education of women -- India; Nutrition -- India
    - India: Women at work, circa 1923-1973 (Box 1009, Folder 12)
      Young women's Christian associations in India provide job skills training, materials and guidance to empower women to be able to earn their own money and participate in a trade. Most of the photographs show women engaged in weaving or textile craft and one photograph shows young women in the Employment Bureau at the YWCA in Bombay, India.
      India; Young Women's Christian associations -- India; Women -- India; Youth -- India; Women -- Employment -- India
    - India: Women's Technical Training Institute, 1973-1974 (Box 1010, Folder 1)
      The Young Women's Christian Association Women's Technical Training Institute offers young women career oriented courses and skills training. Courses such as secretarial skills, medical laboratory, beauty, cosmetology and electronics prepare women for careers in their selected area. Photographs show women in classes and practicing their skills as well as exterior shots of the school building.
      India; Young Women's Christian associations -- India; Women -- India; Women -- Employment -- India; Occupational training -- India
    - India: YWCA School of Social Work, circa 1950-1970 (Box 1010, Folder 2)
      The YWCA School of Social work in New Delhi offers graduate courses in social work to men and women in India. The school, partly funded by the YWCA of the USA Round-the-World Reconstruction Fund, prepares students for field work and practice. Photographs show students studying, participating in classes and practicing field work.
      India; Young Women's Christian associations -- India; Women -- India; Social service -- India; Social work education -- India; Women -- International cooperation
    - Israel: Buildings, circa 1922-1971 (Box 1010, Folder 3)
      Photographs of the interiors and exteriors of young women's Christian association buildings in Israel. Several photographs show damage to buildings due to area conflicts. Photographs also include views of Jerusalem taken from the YWCA building.
      Israel; Young Women's Christian associations -- Israel; Women -- Israel; Housing -- Israel
    - Israel: Jerusalem, circa 1920-1971 (Box 1010, Folder 4)
      Photographs of program activities at young women's Christian associations in Jerusalem. The Jerusalem association offers a diverse program meeting the many needs of the women and girls of Jerusalem. Some activities include a folk dance class (pictured performing a dabke), vocational training, child care programs, nursery schools, day camps and refugee relief.
      Jerusalem -- Israel; Young Women's Christian associations -- Israel; Women -- Israel; Children -- Israel; Refugees -- Israel; Recreation -- Israel; Folk dancing -- Israel; Vocational guidence -- Israel; Women--International cooperation
    - Italy: General, circa 1910-1950 (Box 1010, Folder 5)
      Young women's Christian associations in Italy provide much needed relief and opportunity for the women of Italy following World War II. They help distribute supplies, provide education and offer places for women to meet. Photographs show YWCA members utilizing donated materials and contributing to war relief efforts. Pre-war photographs show the interior and exterior of YWCA buildings.
      Young Women's Christian associations -- Italy; Women -- Italy; Children -- Italy; World War, 1939-1945 -- War work -- Young Women's Christian associations; World War, 1939-1945 -- War work -- Italy; Reconstruction (1939-1951) -- Italy; Women -- International cooperation; Italy
    - Italy: Teen and youth classes, circa 1940-1967 (Box 1010, Folder 6)
      Photographs of classes for teens and youth at young women's Christian associations in Italy. For young children who have left school, YWCA classes supplement their education and offer skills training that can later be used in employment. In Naples, YWCA centers and classes provide a place for children and youth to avoid the crowded homes and streets and work and study.
      Young Women's Christian associations -- Italy; Italy; Women -- Italy; Children -- Italy; Girls -- Italy; Education -- Italy
    - Italy: Negatives (Box 1010, Folder 7)
    - Jamaica, 1961-1967 (Box 1010, Folder 8)
      Photographs of young women's Christian associations activities in Jamaica. Included are photographs from the World YWCA conference on the role of women and of association programming.
      Young Women's Christian associations -- Jamaica; Women -- Jamaica; Youth -- Jamaica; Jamaica
    - Japan: Buildings, circa 1918-1951 (Box 1010, Folder 9)
      Photographs of the interiors and exteriors of young women's Christian association buildings in Japan.
      Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Women -- Japan; Japan
    - Japan: Camping, circa 1949-1963 (Box 1010, Folder 10)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association camp programs in Japan. YWCA's host overnight and day camps for local women and girls. The camps offer a chance for outdoor recreation, handicraft, leadership training and relaxation. Photographs include images of the YWCA Camp at Lake Nojiri, participants in the working mother's camp, handicraft classes and camp groups.
      Japan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Women -- Japan; Camps for girls -- Japan; Outdoor recreation -- Japan; Teenage girls -- Japan; Handicraft -- Japan
    - Japan: Celebrations, ceremonies and pageants, 1918-1963 (Box 1010, Folder 11)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association celebrations, pageants and ceremonies in Japan. Included are photographs of Christmas pageants, World Fellowship Week programs and anniversary celebrations.
      Japan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Women -- Japan; Pageants -- Japan; Special events -- Japan
    - Japan: Children, circa 1921-1963 (Box 1010, Folder 12)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association programs for children in Japan. These programs include child care, kindergartens, and recreation.
      Japan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Children with disabilities -- Japan; Children -- Japan; Child care services -- Japan
    - Japan: Classes, circa 1920-1971 (Box 1010, Folder 13-14, Box 1011, Folder 1)
      Photographs of domestic science, English language and vocational classes at young women's Christian associations in Japan.
      Japan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Women -- Japan; Handicraft -- Japan; Cooking -- Study and teaching -- Japan; Home economics -- Japan; English language -- Study and teaching -- Japan; Women -- International cooperation; Occupational training -- Japan; Secretaries -- Japan; Women -- Employment -- Japan
    - Japan: Conferences, circa 1907-1920 (Box 1011, Folder 2)
      Group photographs at young women's Christian association conferences in Japan.
      Japan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Women -- Japan; Congresses and conventions -- Japan
    - Japan: Contact sheets and negatives, circa 1960-1969 (Box 1011, Folder 3)
      Contact sheets of photographs taken at young women's Christian association clubs, programs and classes.
      Japan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Women -- Japan
    - Japan: Flower arrangement and tea ceremony, circa 1932-1970 (Box 1011, Folder 4)
      As part of their programs, young women's Christian associations in Japan offer classes and training in traditional Japanese customs such as flower arranging, tea ceremonies and calligraphy. Photographs depict participants and instructors in addition to tea ceremonies in progress.
      Japan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Women -- Japan; Flower arrangement, Japanese; Calligraphy, Japanese; Japanese tea ceremony
    - Japan: Groups, circa 1922-1966 (Box 1011, Folder 5)
      Group photographs from young women's Christian association programs, clubs and activities in Japan. The photographs include images of YWCA classes, posed groups and special events.
      Japan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Women -- Japan; Special events -- Japan
    - Japan: Kure scrapbook, 1948 (Box 1011, Folder 6)
      These unbound scrapbook pages document the development of the Kure YWCA in a former navy building. A collaborative effort from the YWCA of Japan and advisory leaders from the YWCA of the USA, the YWCA of Kure brings Christianity and association programs to women in Kure. Among the influential leaders is Ms. Jean Begg. The scrapbook emphasizes the effect the programs have on the lives of women in the post-war society.
      Japan; scrapbooks; Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Women -- Japan; Special events -- Japan; Community organization -- Japan; Women -- International cooperation; Women -- Religious life -- Japan
    - Japan: Miscellaneous, circa 1909-1970 (Box 1011, Folder 7)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association activities, buildings, groups and leaders in Japan and postcards depicting scenes from around Japan. Photographs of buildings include images of damage following an earthquake.
      Postcards; Japan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Women -- Japan; Special events -- Japan; Kanto Earthquake, Japan, 1923; Women--International cooperation
    - Japan: Physical education and recreation, circa 1923-1965 (Box 1011, Folder 8)
      Many young women's Christian associations in Japan offer physical education and recreation programs as part of their regular activities. Photographs include images of girls and women participating in outdoor recreation, swimming, dancing, handicraft and games.
      Japan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Physical education for women -- Japan; Recreation -- Japan; Outdoor recreation -- Japan; Handicraft -- Japan; Women -- International cooperation
    - Japan: Program, circa 1922-1970 (Box 1011, Folder 9)
      Photographs of program activities from young women's Christian associations in Japan. Photographs show women and teenage girls engaged in discussion groups and using association libraries and also include photographs from an association bazaar.
      Japan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Women -- Japan; Special events -- Japan; Forums (Discussion and debate) -- Japan; Women -- International cooperation
    - Japan: Staff and volunteers, circa 1923-1971 (Box 1011, Folder 10)
      Group photographs and snapshots of the staff and volunteers of young women's Christian associations in Japan.
      Japan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Japan; Women -- Japan; Special events -- Japan; Leadership in women
    - Japan: Women at work, circa 1920 (Box 1011, Folder 11)
      Photograph of a woman and a man working at a small doll factory.
      Women -- Japan; Women -- Employment -- Japan; Japan